Nothing but the same anime,
day in day out.
It's like he has no emotions whatsoever.
It sometimes feels like he doesn't even
recognize me as his mother.
That cut on his forehead
will probably leave a scar.
His father does nothing
to help me at all.
He says he's on a business trip today too.
But I know that's a lie.
He's not on any business trip.
To make matters worse,
Satoru just sits watching the same anime.
His father puts all the blame on me.
He thinks it's my fault that
our son was born this way.
I suppose that's why he spites me
by having affairs.
I know.
I'll just have to get my own back...
I'll get back at him...
by committing suicide!
Satoru!
Stop it, Satoru!
What are you doing?
Why do you always do this...?
Why? Why does he behave like that, doctor?
I can't stop thinking I should
just have him committed...
These hospitals are always so dreary...
No smoking in the hospital!
Please go find a smoking area!
Mind your own business, sausage legs!
I'm obviously smoking by the toilet
because I couldn't find the smoking area!
Mr. Katsuragi, no smoking in the hospital.
Hayashi!
If you hurried the hell up,
I wouldn't have some woman bothering me!
I was out in the car park looking for you.
Shut it!
And don't even think about showing me
your endoscopy trick.
Mr. Katsuragi.
I think that kid might be one.
You can tell?
Maybe.
I was like that as a kid too.
Oh no, looks like I got
the wrong return time.
I can't take much more...
Enough! Why am I the only one to suffer?
You always take it out on me...
Hey. How's it going?
This place doesn't seem like much fun.
Who are you, mister?
I'm a bit like Matasaburo,
the wind spirit.
Matasa...?
Right... I guess you're too young
to know that story.
So, this is all your mom's
inner turmoil, is it?
You sure visit some scary places.
Is that why you always sit so still?
Yeah.
You visit these scary places because
the portal to your heart is always open.
Portal?
A portal's like a door.
It can be opened and closed.
You mean the Everywhere Door?
The Everywhere Door?
That there.
Huh... pretty impressive, kid.
Why d'you say that?
Using an "image" like that
is something not everybody can do.
Now, let's use this door to go to
your favorite place in the world.
My favorite place in the world...?
Ah, right...
You don't have
any memories of your own yet.
Let's try it this way then. I'll share
a place from my memories with you.
Okay, let's open the door together.
Here we go.
This is the place in my memories
I like the most.
Mr. Matasa, this place isn't scary at all.
Doesn't the wind feel great?
The wind can travel anywhere.
Anywhere?
That's right.
The wind taught me something.
That I have the power
to freely shape my future.
The ability to mold it as I choose.
An ability called an "image".
Let's make this place your "peak".
My peak?
So...
The place that holds
your most treasured memories.
Any bad memories, you should put away
in another place, your "valley".
If you make a "peak" and a "valley"
like that,
you can live a normal life,
the same as everyone else.
Now, listen closely.
This is the most important thing of all.
Keep your peak and your valley
closed to all others.
Don't let anyone touch or alter them
in any way.
IN THE LANDSCAPE OF THE HUMAN MEMORY,
"THEY" GAVE NAMES TO JUST TWO LOCI,
"PEAKS" AND "VALLEYS".
THE CRUSHERS
Say, Tsukasa.
What do you say we open up
a bar, down the line?
I bet it'd be a lot of fun.
Somewhere like this dingy drinking hole.
Dingy is it?
Sure, but I'll be the manager.
Says who?
In that case, I get to be the director.
Check it out, fireworks!
Or should I say, waterworks!
What're you doing, dumbass!
You're getting everything wet!
-I told you to put the parasol away first!
-You ain't scary from up there, man.
Hey, I heard that, Hiroki!
Kenji's hearing is incredible...
Dammit. Now it's going to get all moldy.
Hey. Go get changed, you two.
What's it to you? We'll just dry off.
Who do you think our customers are?
I ain't running a gay bar here,
so enough with the wet t-shirts.
Watch the wandering hands, you perv!
Let's go get changed, Hiroki.
I'm calling sexual harassment.
Gimme a break.
Hey. Those two who went up to
the second floor,
are they related to Yokota?
Yokota? He left this place a while back.
Oh?
One day he just came out with
"I'm headed for Bali."
He's not coming back for 2 or 3 years.
So I decided to rent that floor out
to someone else.
And after all the years
we'd worked together...
Still, the idea of not having orders
barked at me gives me a sense of relief.
Yet I detect a tinge of melancholy.
Nah.
I'm just bored 'cause I've got no one
to argue with anymore.
But I've got these two lively
idiots with me now, so...
I figured I'd put them to work in the bar.
Thanks, but I'm not smoking these days.
Just tell me you're not subbing
any of my jobs to them. Are you?
Don't sweat it, man.
I can handle the work you give me
just fine on my own.
Glad to hear it.
By the way, Kenji,
you got the keys to your van?
Yeah, sure.
I'm swapping cars with you for a while.
I'll tell you where to go, tonight.
I'll leave your van at the spot.
Put the item you pick up in the trunk of
this car. Leave the spare key behind too.
You know how the rest goes.
Don't go asking too many questions, right?
Don't worry.
I didn't even ask my best friend
why he took off for Bali.
Dammit, man!
This is too much for one guy.
Yokota, you pain in the ass,
leaving me to do all the heavy lifting.
We'd split everything
down the middle until now.
Job done, I guess.
Shit!
The job ain't done at all!
Mr. Katsuragi,
there's no spare key in here.
Crap, this is bad.
There's someone there.
Tell me that's not the cops.
Get a move on.
The sun'll be up soon.
Phew, it's Mr. Katsuragi.
Mr. Ka...
Something wrong?
No. Just my imagination.
What the hell?
Aren't you supposed to be in Bali, Yokota?
-What speed you doing now, then?
-100 miles an hour!
Hey... what the hell's
going on here, Yokota?
How d'you fancy taking to the skies?
Yeah!
If you head back the way we came,
there's a tunnel.
Hit the accelerator
as soon as you leave it.
Do that and you'll touch the sky.
What?
-Look at that, it's time to go.
-Yeah!
Steam train! Steam train! All aboard!
Here we go! Choo-choo!
Crap!
Yokota...
Yokota.
Yokota. Yokota. Yokota.
Yokota!
Kenji. You really don't remember?
We both saw it when we were
retrieving those counterfeit bills.
What were you on about?
Counterfeit bills?
What's going on here...?
What happened to that spare key?
Hey, you listening over there?
The spare key...
I told you to leave it behind.
What? You forgot?
You really are useless.
Fine. Let's meet at the usual park.
I really am not a morning person.
The dew reminds me of
school girls' sweaty gym socks.
This is your payment.
Go wipe your ass with it!
Whoa. No need to be so rude.
I've hidden the key in a safe place.
If anything happens to me,
it goes straight to the police.
What're you laughing at?
You just reminded me of another guy who
said the very same thing not long ago.
Turned out he wasn't even bluffing,
and the key actually did get sent
to the police.
That bastard Yokota gave me
a bunch of extra work.
Besides, who wants to work with
someone with no sense of humor?
You murderer!
I'm not interested in what you think
but I do want that key of yours.
You've got it on you, right?
Hurtling off the road like that,
he'd clearly lost his mind.
Just what did you assholes do to him?
You were bluffing when
you said you'd quit too.
I know you really want a smoke.
I see right through you.
Now, I guess...
it's just a matter of getting
the information from you.
I've called in the crushers.
I'd watch my back if I were you.
The "crushers"?
Really, Kaori? Your family owns a yacht?
Very cool.
When's that, then?
Hey!
What's that face for?
What about your face
when you're talking to Kaori?
It's her fault we're working so late
the morning paper's already come.
She's an important client.
Children should keep quiet
when the adults are talking.
Who you calling a child?
You, because you are!
Save the foreplay for after breakfast!
We're having a fight...
Whatever. Cut it out!
Hey man, you can't just
walk in as you please.
Listen, you two.
How d'you both like the sound
of managing the bar?
I know it's sudden, but I was thinking
of checking out Bali for 2 or 3 years.
You guys wanted to run a bar, right?
He who runs away,
lives to fight another day.
It's all the bosses' fault.
Sinking those fake bills right next to
that body encased in concrete...
Kenji and Yokota were bound to see it!
Their faces were white as sheets
when they came up.
Of course, the bosses think
sorting such a mess is easy.
"Just make them forget everything,"
they said.
How about a bit more of
a head's up next time?
Then I end up with Yokota pretending
he didn't see anything
and Kenji really believing
he didn't see anything.
Of course Yokota's going to wonder
what the hell's up!
Makes sense that he'd steal
a banknote or two to protect himself.
Well...
I think you've done pretty well
considering you don't use an image.
Satoru.
If you've got something to say,
don't mince your words.
If you just transfer the rent money,
you boys can keep
whatever profits are made.
I'll do it! I'll totally do it!
How much is the rent anyway?
I'll send more details when I get there.
Just make sure you tell
people that I'm in Bali.
When really I'll be in LA,
far away from Bali!
Anyway, I'd better get going.
Huh? This is addressed to me...
That was on the floor
when the newspaper came in.
On the floor?
I even went up to the 3rd floor to give it
to you but you weren't in.
AIRPLANE TICKET TO LA,
NOT BALI
KAORI
Weird... I thought I broke it.
It's Kaori.
Hello?
Sorry about that, my smartphone's
on the fritz at the moment.
She hung up...
Gimme. I'll take a look for you.
You saying you can fix it?
Is there something wrong?
You're really sweating
and acting a bit weird.
Weird...?
You two are the weird ones here!
What the hell're you doing?
I'm repairing his phone.
What does it look like?
Are you alright?
Huh?
What's up with you?
You're looking kind of pale.
Yeah...
Weird...
I must be tired.
Man, my head hurts.
I'm just grabbing some water.
You got a headache?
This is the best cure for a headache.
What the...!
Hey.
What's that doing there?
I'm supposed...
to have quit.
Quit messing with me!
What're you doing, man?
You're gonna hurt somebody!
You're losing it, dude!
That's it...
It was Katsuragi!
He did something to me!
There you go again.
You don't get it! Listen to me!
He knows some guys who can
get inside people's heads!
Those freaks know how
to bend people to their will!
I'm telling you, it's true!
They made Yokota drive off a cliff!
I saw it with my own eyes!
You gotta believe me.
Would I be acting this nuts,
if it wasn't true?
Don't worry.
We believe you.
No...
Are you two...
the crushers?
I knew something fishy was going on.
Out of the blue, the guy's off to Bali.
I mean, who does that?
But I never would've guessed
Yokota was a murderer.
Then again, it doesn't surprise me
all that much to be honest.
The guy lived like he'd given up hope
long ago.
I knew he'd meet a bad end
one way or another.
Pretty awful guy, that Yokota.
I'm sure he was a pain in your ass too.
You've got that right! I even got taken in
for questioning 'cause of him!
But don't worry about a thing.
I didn't mention anything
about our dealings.
I'm not the slightest bit
concerned about that.
Oh hey. You're back.
Who do we have here? Relatives of yours?
Nah, nothing like that.
I've been renting Yokota's room
to these two.
Did you finish packing your things?
Yes.
We took the liberty of
using the furniture.
Thanks for having us.
Well, I guess no one wants to stay
in a murderer's room.
Yokota taking off like that
caused you boys some problems, too.
Hopefully this will
make up for your troubles.
No need.
Huh?
Keep it for cigarette money.
What? Seriously?
Lucky me!
Goodbye, then.
Artist: Ranjo Miyake